<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" []>
<?rfc strict="yes" ?>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes" ?>
<?rfc subcompact="no" ?>

<rfc category="std" ipr="trust200902" docName="draft-ietf-grow-bgp-reject-05" submissionType="IETF">

    <front>

        <title abbrev="BGP Default Reject">Default EBGP Route Propagation Behavior Without Policies</title>

        <author fullname="Jared Mauch" initials="J." surname="Mauch">
            <organization abbrev="Akamai">Akamai Technologies</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>8285 Reese Lane</street>
                    <code>Michigan 48103</code>
                    <city>Ann Arbor</city>
                    <country>US</country>
                </postal>
                <email>jared@akamai.com</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Job Snijders" initials="J." surname="Snijders">
            <organization abbrev="NTT">NTT Communications</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>Theodorus Majofskistraat 100</street>
                    <code>1065 SZ</code>
                    <city>Amsterdam</city>
                    <country>NL</country>
                </postal>
				<email>job@ntt.net</email>
			</address>
		</author>

        <author fullname="Greg Hankins" initials="G." surname="Hankins">
            <organization>Nokia</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>777 E. Middlefield Road</street>
                    <city>Mountain View</city>
                    <region>CA</region>
                    <code>94043</code>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </postal>
                <email>greg.hankins@nokia.com</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <date />

        <area>Routing</area>
        <workgroup>Global Routing Operations</workgroup>
        <keyword>reject</keyword>
        <keyword>BGP</keyword>
        <keyword>EBGP</keyword>

        <abstract>
            <t>
                This document defines the default behavior of a BGP speaker when there is no import or export policy associated with an External BGP session.
            </t>
        </abstract>

        <note title="Requirements Language">
            <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT", "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as described in <xref target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.
            </t>
        </note>

    </front>


    <middle>
        <section anchor="Introduction" title="Introduction">
            <t>
                There are BGP routing security issues that need to be addressed to make the Internet more stable. 
                Route leaks <xref target="RFC7908" /> are part of the problem, but software defects or operator misconfigurations can contribute too. 
                This document provides guidance to BGP <xref target="RFC4271" /> implementers to improve the default level of Internet routing security.
            </t>

            <t>
                Many deployed BGP speakers send and accept any and all route announcements between their BGP neighbors by default.
                This practice dates back to the early days of the Internet, where operators were permissive in sending routing information to allow all networks to reach each other.
                As the Internet has become more densely interconnected, the risk of a misbehaving BGP speaker poses significant risks to Internet routing.
            </t>

            <t>
                This specification intends to improve this situation by requiring the explicit configuration of a BGP import and export policy for any External BGP (EBGP) session such as customers, peers, or confederation boundaries for all enabled address families.
                When this solution is implemented, BGP speakers do not accept or send routes without policies configured on EBGP sessions.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="Solution" title="Solution">
            <t>
                The following requirements apply to all BGP speakers:
                <list style="symbols">
                    <t>A BGP speaker MUST consider any routes advertised by an EBGP peer ineligible for route selection (<xref target="RFC4271">section 9.1.1</xref>), if no import policy was configured for the peer.</t>
                    <t>A BGP speaker MUST NOT advertise any routes to an EBGP peer, if no export policy was configured for the peer.</t>
                    <t>A BGP speaker SHOULD fall back to an "import nothing" and "export nothing" mode following failure of internal components, such as a policy engine.</t>
                    <t>A BGP speaker MAY provide a configuration option to disable the preceding behaviors, but it MUST implement them by default.</t>
                </list>
            </t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="Acknowledgments" title="Acknowledgments">
            <t>
                The authors would like to thank the following people for their comments, support and review: Shane Amante, Christopher Morrow, Robert Raszuk, Greg Skinner, Adam Chappell, Sriram Kotikalapudi, Brian Dickson, Jeffrey Haas, John Heasley, Ignas Bagdonas, Donald Smith, and Dale Worley.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="Security" title="Security Considerations">
            <t>
                This document addresses a basic routing security issue caused by permissive default routing policy configurations.
                Operators need implementers to address this problem with more secure defaults to mitigate collateral damage on Internet routing. 
                Inadvertent or adversarial advertisements cause business impact that can be mitigated by a secure default behavior.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="IANA Considerations">
            <t>
                This document has no actions for IANA.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="Contributors">
        <t>
            The following people contributed to successful deployment of solution described in this document:
        </t>
        <figure>
            <preamble></preamble>
            <artwork>
Jakob Heitz
Cisco

Email: jheitz@cisco.com
</artwork>
            <postamble></postamble>
        </figure>
        <figure>
            <preamble></preamble>
            <artwork>
Ondrej Filip
CZ.NIC

Email: ondrej.filip@nic.cz
</artwork>
            <postamble></postamble>
        </figure>
    </section>

    </middle>

    <back>

        <references title="Normative References">
            <?rfc include="reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
            <?rfc include="reference.RFC.4271.xml"?>
        </references>

        <references title="Informative References">
            <?rfc include="reference.RFC.7908.xml"?>
        </references>

    </back>

</rfc>
