<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
<!-- A set of on-line citation libraries are maintained on the xml2rfc web site.
     The next line defines an entity named RFC2629, which contains the necessary XML
     for the reference element, and is used much later in the file.  This XML contains an
     anchor (also RFC2629) which can be used to cross-reference this item in the text.
     You can also use local file names instead of a URI.  The environment variable
     XML_LIBRARY provides a search path of directories to look at to locate a
     relative path name for the file. There has to be one entity for each item to be
     referenced. -->
<!ENTITY RFC2119 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC4271 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4271.xml">
<!ENTITY nbsp    "&#160;">
]>

<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='rfc2629.xslt' ?>

<rfc
    category="std"
    ipr="trust200902"
    docName="draft-mauch-bgp-reject-00.txt" >
    <?rfc strict="yes" ?>
    <?rfc comments="no" ?>
    <?rfc inline="no" ?>
    <?rfc editing="no" ?>
    <?rfc toc="yes"?>
    <?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
    <?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
    <?rfc symrefs="no"?>
    <?rfc sortrefs="yes" ?>
    <?rfc compact="yes" ?>
    <?rfc subcompact="no" ?>

<front>

    <title abbrev="BGP-DEFAULT-REJECT">By default reject propagation when no policy is associated with a BGP peering session.</title>

    <author fullname="Jared Mauch" initials="J." surname="Mauch">
        <organization abbrev="NTT">NTT Communications, Inc.</organization>
        <address>
            <postal>
                <street>8285 Reese Lane</street>
                <code>Michigan 48103</code>
                <city>Ann Arbor</city>
                <country>US</country>
            </postal>
            <email>jmauch@us.ntt.net</email>
        </address>
    </author>

    <author
        fullname="Job Snijders"
        initials="J."
        surname="Snijders">
        <organization abbrev="NTT">NTT Communications, Inc.</organization>
        <address>
            <postal>
		<street></street>
		<code></code>
		<city>Amsterdam</city>
                <country>NL</country>
            </postal>
                <email>job@ntt.net</email>
        </address>
    </author>


    <date year="2015" month="July"/>

    <area>Routing</area>
    <workgroup>Internet Engineering Task Force</workgroup>

    <abstract>
           <t>This document defines the default behaviour of a BGP speaker when
            no explicit policy is associated with a BGP peering session.</t>
    </abstract>

    <note title="Foreword">
        <t>A placeholder to list general observations about this document.</t>
    </note>

    <note title="Requirements Language">
        <t>The key words &quot;MUST&quot;, &quot;MUST NOT&quot;,
        &quot;REQUIRED&quot;, &quot;SHALL&quot;, &quot;SHALL NOT&quot;,
        &quot;SHOULD&quot;, &quot;SHOULD NOT&quot;, &quot;RECOMMENDED&quot;,
        &quot;MAY&quot;, and &quot;OPTIONAL&quot; in this document are to be
        interpreted as described in <xref target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.
        </t>
    </note>

</front>


<middle>
    <section anchor="Introduction" title="Introduction">
<t>
    BGP speakers have many default settings which need to be revisited
    as part of improving the routing ecosystem.  There is a need to provide
    guidace to BGP implementors for the default behaviors of a well functioning
    internet ecosystem.  Routing leaks <xref target="RL" /> are part of the
    problem, but software defects and operator misconfigurations are just a few
    of the attacks on internet stability we aim to address.
</t>

<t>
    Usually BGP speakers accept all routes from a configured peer or
    neighbor. This practice dates back to the early days of internet protocols
    in being very permissive in offering routing information to allow all
    networks to reach each other.  With the core of the internet becoming more
    densely interconnected the risk of a misbehaving edge device or BGP
    speaking customer poses signficiant risks to the reachability of critical
    services.
</t>

<t>
    This proposal intends to solve this situation with the requiring the
    explicity configuration of BGP policy for any non-iBGP speaking session
    such as customers, peers or confederation boundaries. When this solution is
    implemented, devices will no longer pass routes without explicit
    policy.
</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Definition" title="Definitions and Acronyms">
      <t><list style="symbols">
		<t>BGP: Border Gateway Protocol <xref target="RFC4271" /></t>
        </list>
      </t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Requirements" title="Solution Requirements">
    	<t>The following requirements apply to the solution described in this document:
        <list style="symbols">
			<t>Software MUST NOT accept routes from an eBGP peer without an operator configuring a policy</t>
			<t>Software MUST NOT send routes to an eBGP peer without an operator configuring a policy</t>
                        <t>Software MUST NOT require a configuration directive to operate in this mode.</t>
			<t>Software MUST provide protection from internal failures preventing the advertisement and acceptance of routes</t>
			<t>Software MAY provide a configuration option to disable this security capability.</t>
			</list>
		  </t>
    </section>


    <section anchor="Acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>The authors would like to thank the following people for their comments and support: [TBD].</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Security" title="Security Considerations">
		<t>This document addresses the basic security posture of a BGP speaking device within a network. Operators have a need for implementors to address the problem through a behavior change to mitigate against possible attacks from a permissive security posture.  Attacks and inadvertent advertisements cause business impact necessitating this default behavior.</t>
    </section>
</middle>

<back>

    <references title="Normative References">
        &RFC2119;
        &RFC4271;

    </references>

    <references title="Informative References">

        <reference anchor="RL" target="https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-sriram-idr-route-leak-detection-mitigation">
            <front>
                <title>Methods for Detection and Mitigation of BGP Route Leaks</title>
                <author>
                    <organization/>
                </author>
                <date/>
            </front>
        </reference>

    </references>


</back>

</rfc>
